Kohei Hiraga (Kohei Ueno)

Senior Software Engineer at LY Corporation / Node.js Core Collaborator

+81 90-4242-2296 / kohei.ueno119@gmail.com / github.com/cola119 / linkedin.com/in/kohei-ueno

As a Senior Software Engineer with five years of experience at LY Corporation, I specialize in developing web applications and the JavaScript SDK for the MINI App platform with a daily active user base of tens of millions. My expertise in JavaScript and Web technology is further demonstrated through significant contributions to open-source projects including Node.js and WebKit.

Experience

LY Corporation Senior Software Engineer

Tokyo, Japan April 2023 - Present

As a tech lead, I led a team of 4 Front-End developers and collaborated with over 15 people to build a MINI App platform called LINE Front-End Framework (LIFF) and its authentication infrastructure. The following experiences highlight my leadership and ability to identify solutions and navigate ambiguity in situations where problems aren't clearly defined and traditional methods may not apply.

- Spearheaded a culture of quality and growth by leading code reviews, facilitating technical discussions, and delegating growth-promoting tasks, while fostering cross-functional collaboration to boost overall project success.
- Implemented a task management strategy to effectively prioritize and progress key SDK feature development, which maximizes output and customer satisfaction under limited resources.
- Initiated and led the development of open-sourced devtools and CLI tools for LIFF, which facilitate debugging, automate tasks, and improve app integration, enhancing the overall quality of LIFF apps and fostering a developer community.

LY Corporation Software Engineer

Tokyo, Japan July 2019 - April 2023

- Participated in a panel discussion about the sustainability of open-source software, providing insights from the perspective of a major open-source (Node.js) maintainer.
- Developed SPA-based web apps for browsers and LIFF using React and Vue.js, optimizing performance for a smooth experience across all devices, including lower-end models.

Node.js Project Core Collaborator (Maintainer)

Remote August 2022 - Present

- Submitted over 40 pull requests to implement new features and fix bugs with a particular focus on the `node:inspector` module with my interest and expertise in debugging methodology.
- Mentored individuals interested in Node.js and open-source contributions, facilitating pair programming and code review to enable their active contributions and hands-on experience.

WebKit Individual Contributor

Remote September 2023 - Present

• Submitted over 15 patches, primarily focused on the WebVTT area, leading to a substantial improvement in WebVTT API compatibility from 88.98% to 96.61%. Link to my patch list.

Education

Tokyo Institute of Technology Bachelor's degree, Computer Science April 2015 - March 2019

Proficiencies

Languages: Japanese (Native), English (Fluent), JavaScript, TypeScript, C, C++, HTML, CSS